Guide to the International Women's Year audio recordings 1977
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
International Women's Year audio recordings
1977
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0236
65 audiocassettes, 4 reel-to-reel audiotapes
The International Women's Year audio recordings document workshops and meetings that occurred at Utah's 1977 IWY conference in Salt Lake City.
Historical Note
Under the auspices of the United Nations, 1975 was proclaimed "International Women's Year" (IWY). A world conference was held from June 23 to July 4 of that year in Mexico City. As a result of the conference, the United Nations declared a "Women's Decade," a ten-year period in which women in all parts of the world would work to gain all the rights of full citizenship. Following the Mexico conference, the United States congress established the National Commission for the Observance of International Women's Year. Women's conferences were to be held in every state before the first day of July 1977. Utah's first Coordinating Committee meeting was held in Salt Lake City in February 1977.
The International Women's Year audio recordings document workshops and meetings that occurred at Utah's 1977 IWY conference in Salt Lake City. Some recordings are of poor quality. All recordings have been digitized and are available to listen to on compact disc.
Materials are arranged in series by workshops and by committee meeting, plenary sessions and task forces. Workshops are arranged alphabetically by meeting subject. Committee meetings, plenary sessions and task forces are arranged chronologially and by meeting type.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the International Women's Year records (Ms 236) in the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections.
International Women's Year (1977: Salt Lake City, Utah--Archives; International Women's Year, 1975--Utah; Clubs and Societies; Sound Recordings; Sound recordings
- Workshops, 1977; Audiocassette
  Worhshops consist of discussions or panel presentations on the designated subject, followed by the formation through parliamentary procedure of recommendations by the session attendees. These resolutions would later be voted on by Utah delegates in committee meetings and plenary sessions and ultimately submitted to the national IWY conference in Huston.
  - Aging, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 1-6)
  - Arts and humanities, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 7)
  - Basic needs, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 8-10)
  - Child development, 1977; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 11-12)
  - Employment, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 13-15)
  - Enforcement of laws, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 16)
  - Family violence: child abuse, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 17-18)
  - Family violence: wife abuse, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 19-20)
  - Health: health education, mental health, reproductive health, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 21-26)
  - Homemakers, legal status, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 27-28)
  - Lifestyles, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 29-32)
    These workshops were for discussion only and presented no recommendations.
  - Lifestyles duplicates, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 33-36)
    Recordings 33-36 are duplicates of recordings 29-32. Additional compact discs have not been created for these cassettes.
  - Media, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 37-38)
  - Men, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 39-42)
  - Polarization, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 43-44)
  - Power, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 45)
  - Rape, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 46-47)
  - Women as students, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 48-51)
  - Women offenders, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 52-53)
  - Young women: life span planning, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 54-55)
  - Young women: teenage pregnancy, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 56-57)
- Committee meetings, plenary sessions and task forces, 1977; Audiocassette
  - Coordinating committee meetings, 1977 June 25; 1977 June 29; 1977 July 21; 1977 July 27; Audiocassette (Cassette 58-65)
    Coordinating committee meetings consist of recordings of committees planning the Salt Lake City IWY and reviewing the recommendations brought forth from it. Thorugh parliamentary process the committee members decide which recommendations to put forth at the national conference in Huston. Recommendations are reviewed according to workshop subject.
    Items 61 and 65 are of such poor quality as to be completely unintelligible; items 61 and 65 are not available to listen to on compact disc.
  - Plenary sessions, 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 66-67)
    Includes speeches of Helvi Sipila and Lola Redford.
  - Task forces, 1977 June 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 68-69)